Elaine Lagon

Fort Worth, TX 76123 | 817-480-3431 | emlportfolio@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/elaine-drum-female **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/elagonwork/

Portfolio: https://elaine-drum-female.github.io/new-portfolio-site/

SUMMARY

Front-End Developer with extensive web development experience updating and maintaining internal and external websites using content management systems for in-house companies. Graduated Summa Cum Laude and holds a Bachelor of Science in Multimedia Design and Web Development. My strongest skills are design and usability.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery, Git, GitHub, Responsive Design, Twitter Bootstrap
- Wireframing, Firebase, Client-Side-Storage, Adobe Creative Cloud Products
- Node.js, MySQL and Sequelize, Handlebars, React, AJAX Request, APIs

PROJECTS

Bootstrap Portfolio | Github Repository | My Bootstrap Portfolio

The goal of this project was to create a portfolio website using Bootstrap's framework.

Role: Sole Developer

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

RPG Game | Github Repository | RPG Game

Endless fighting between user created characters.

Role: Front-End Developer

• HTML, CSS, AJAX Request, APIs, jQuery

BamazonCustomer | Github Repository

Create an Amazon-like storefront with the MySQL skills you learned this unit. The app will take in orders from customers and deplete stock from the store's inventory.

Role: Sole Developer

• *jQuery, MySQL, Inquirer, Node.js*

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DESIGNER

JANUARY 2017 - AUGUST 2018

The Insource Group, Inc., Dallas, TX

Client: First Command Financial Services, Inc., Fort Worth, TX

- Redesigned specific sections of web content to be inline with mobile first design
- Generated an inventory list of less than 500 webpage links from both public websites and delivered final product in less than a week within a 2-3-week deadline
- Assisted the Marketing Insights Manager by writing out HTML code for a simple template used to help visualize survey collection concept, and imagery prior to sending out to Advisors

Digital Alchemy, Inc., Fort Worth, TX

- Recommended the best designer in-house by assigned clients and supervisor
- Produced a quick mockup for client and was approved same day
- Implemented an idea to the CEO to help speed up process of building a comment card
- Launched from start to finish 25+ email templates per month

WEB DEVELOPER / WEB DESIGNER INTERN

OCTOBER 2013- JANUARY 2014

Nautilus Hyosung America, Inc., Irving, TX

- Designed and coded a 30 second advertisement banner at 18fps within 48 hours
- Devised a new idea for our tagline

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

TRAINING DEVELOPMENT ASSISTANT

SEPTEMBER 2015 - DECEMBER 2016

Shermco Industries, Inc., Irving, TX

- Developed Shermco U Resource Catalog less than a month with 50% done in two days
- Brainstormed and implemented the Shermco U flyer and produced draft on same day

CLERICAL ASSISTANT

JANUARY 2008- APRIL 2013

AXA-ADVISORS, Fort Worth, TX

- Entered 100 clients into the address book in one day
- Handled large file stack of client folders in less than a week
- Copied and compiled large stacks of Commission Statements to be mailed out on the same day

EDUCATION

NOVEMBER 2018

Web Development Certification

SMU, TX

Bachelor of Science in Multimedia Design and Web Development

Summa Cum Laude

DeVry University, Irving, TX

Associates of Applied Science in Information Technology

Tarrant County College, Fort Worth, TX

AWARDS

Certificate in Creating Web Pages

LoneStar College, Conroe, TX

Certificate in Creating Web Graphics

LoneStar College, Conroe, TX